Blake Condrey

• blake.condrey@outlook.com

• www.blakecondrey.com

◆Active TS/SCI

◆ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/blakecondrey ◆ GitHub: github.com/blakecondrey

Full Stack Software Engineer

Results-focused, growth-oriented Full Stack Software Engineer with a demonstrated distinction in the Defense and Space Industry. Propensity in delivering highly scalable services and world-class product experiences with proven skills in full stack React.js and .NET development, sharp adaptability, customer empathy, and creative problem-solving skills realized from 6+ years of servant leadership experience in the fast-paced sales and Defense industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS/PROJECTS

Languages/Technologies:

React JS | Node.js | JavaScript | ASP.NET MVC Core | C# | T-SQL | Python | Cloud Services

CROWNFiT

https://crwnfit.herokuapp.com/

- MERN Full stack web app rendering a mock e-commerce website for men's and women's casual and fitness clothing.
- Built with React, Redux, React Hooks, React Suspense, React Router, GraphQL, Context API, Redux-Saga, and Stripe Payments, deployed with Firebase.

Sorting Visualization Tool

https://blakecondrey.github.io/sortingvisualizer/

- Web App that generates an array of columns, and visualizes the bubble sort, insertion sort, selection sort, merge sort, and quick sort algorithms.
- Built with JavaScript, Responsive Web Design Technologies, deployed on Heroku.

Python-Flask News Aggregator

https://blakecondreynewsagg.herokuapp.com/

- Flask Web App which utilizes the newsapi-python REST API to curate an aggregated news page.
- Built with Flask Framework implementing SQLAlchemy and Web Forms, UI/UX Tools, and Linux Apache

EDUCATION

Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

Oct. 2021 - Feb. 2022

Successful completion of the 18-week Microsoft Cloud Applications Development program designed to cultivate
professional Software Engineers by developing soft skills and technical expertise through producing real-world
projects applying pair-programming concepts and professional development workshops.

Southern New Hampshire University, GPA 3.9

Expected Graduation May 2023

B.S. Computer Science – Software Engineering

Distance Learning/Manchester, NH

WORK EXPERIENCE

United States Air Force

Jan. 2018 – Present Colorado Springs, CO

Command Post, Shift Supervisor

 Communicated daily to senior Pentagon directors via tailored reports with real-time command and control data and situational awareness which enabled the direction of time-critical decisions to sixteen units operating \$22.6B in space satellites and ground radars with no mission or product losses.

- Developed emergency management and disaster preparedness program across four installations, five Air Force organizations, and over 30 geographically separated units, that continually safeguards 25,000 personnel and \$5B in assets.
- Deciphered 230 emergency time-sensitive messages to direct base-defense augmentation, alert base directors of sabotage
 or acts of war, and report to defense headquarters of completed postures at a 100% success rate within four measured
 components of a two-minute window, protecting 440,000 civilians and 25,000 DoD members.

Verizon Wireless Jul. 2015 – Jul. 2017

Solutions Specialist

Chattanooga, TN

- Engaged with walk-in customers to discover needs and expose shortfalls, producing game changing solutions that resulted in 168% year-over-year increased sales revenue.
- Developed product bundles by leveraging existing quantity discounts to provide customers with the best wireless solutions, exceeding sales targets by 130% for 18 consecutive months.